A Guide to the Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1977-1981, RG 33 FA1503
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1977-1981, RG 33
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, David
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978
Mauze, Abby Rockefeller
FA1503
276.49 Cubic Feet 724 document boxes
Arrangement
Original order. Alphabetical, in 37 series, primarily by subject/topic.
File Plan
Former Classification: III 33
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research in accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller Estate, January 2019. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
The 1977-1981 general files chronicle management of the philanthropic affairs of the third generation of the Rockefeller family primarily David Rockefeller and Laurance S. Rockefeller with limited documentation of the actions of John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Nelson A. Rockefeller.
Over the years the Rockefeller family has been involved in virtually all aspects of modern philanthropy at the local, national and international levels through their foundation activities as well as their individual personal giving. Major interests include: physical and mental health, conservation, education, international relations, politics, population, religion, social welfare, the visual and performing arts, cultural exchange programs, and economic and social development of underdeveloped areas.
The general files primarily consist of correspondence, reports, pamphlets, memoranda, charters and certificates of incorporation, minutes and meeting records as well as documentation of contributions, finance and investment materials, real estate, newspaper clippings, diaries, notebooks, calendars, audio tapes, and printed material.
Related Materials
FA1502 Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1962-1996, Index Cards, RG 3-RG 44.
- Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1977-1981; 33
  - A, 1977-1981; 1
    - A - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture - A-Z (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Agriculture - IRI Research Institute, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Agriculture - Emergency Land Fund (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture - National Land for People Foundation (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arts, 1977-1981; 2
    - Arts - A-Am (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Arts - An-C (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
    - Arts - Barnes, Mrs. Clara (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Arts - D-N (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
    - Arts - O-Z (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - AFL-CIO National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees District 1199 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - American Council for the Arts (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - American Crafts Council (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - American Federation of the Arts (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - American Writers Congress (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Arts, Education and Americans, Inc (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Business Committee for the Arts (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Business Committee for the Arts - Minutes-Meetings (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Business Committee for the Arts - Printed Material (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Century Association (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Children's Art Carnival (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Chidren's Art Carnival - Contribution (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cultural Council Foundation (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - A-Z (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - Board of Directors (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - Contributions (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - Minutes-Meetings - Annual (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - Minutes-Meetings - Board of Directors (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - Minutes-Meetings - Executive Committee (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts - Printed Matter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - McDowell Colony, Inc. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Municipal Art Society of New York (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Dance - A-M (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
    - Dance - N-Z (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Films - A-F (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
    - Films - G-O (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
    - Films - P-Z (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Films - Accord Research and Educational Associates (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Films - Hudson River Film Company (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Galleries - A-Z (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
    - Libraries - A-Z (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Libraries - Lyndon Baines Johnson Library (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Libraries - Pierpont Morgan Library (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Libraries - New York Public Library (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Libraries - New York Public Library - Contributions (Box 16, Folder 3-4, Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Libraries - President Ford Library-Museum Fund (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Memorials (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Museums - A-C (Box 17, Folder 4-6)
    - Museums - D-Nd (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
    - Museums - Ne-Z (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
    - Museums - Academy of Natural Sciences (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Museums - Academy of Natural Sciences - Meetings (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Museums - American Association of Museums (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Museums - American Museum of Natural History (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Printed Material (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Bernice P. Bishop Museum (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Museums - Buffalo Bill Historical Center (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Buffalo Bill Historical Center - Printed Material (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
    - Museums - Buffalo Bill Historical Center - Frederick Remington Studio (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Frick Collection (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Museums - The Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Hudson River Museum (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Museums - Israel Museum (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Museums - Israel Museum - Printed Material (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Museums - Institute for Contemporary Art (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Louis Leakey Memorial Institute for African Prehistory (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Museums - Maine Maritime Museum (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Contributions (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    - Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Finances (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Michael C. Rockefeller Wing (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Printed Matter (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    - Museums - Museum of the American Indian - Heye Foundation (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Museum of the City of New York (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Museums - Museum of the City of New York - Laurance S. Rockefeller (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Mass (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - A-Z (Box 26, Folder 1-4)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Board of Trustees (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Condominium (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Condominium - NYC Trust for Cultural Resources - Charles H. Shaw material (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Children's Art Carnival - Contributions (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Finances (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Fund Raising (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Minutes-Meetings (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - NYS Council on the Arts (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Printed Material (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Mrs. John D. Rockefeller 3rd - A-Z (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Museums - Nassau County Museum of Fine Art (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Pacific Northwest Indian Center, Inc. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Museums - Philadelphia Museum of Art (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Museums - Portland Museum of Art, Maine (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - A-N (Box 30, Folder 2-4)
    - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - O-Z (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Smithsonian Institution (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - National Anthropological Film Center (Box 31, Folder 3-4, Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - Printed Matter (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - Smithsonian National Associates (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - A-Z (Box 694, Folder 3)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum, 1972-1981 (Box 694, Folder 4-5)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Board of Directors (Box 695, Folder 1)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Finances (Box 695, Folder 2-3)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Fund Raising (Box 695, Folder 4)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Minutes-Meetings (Box 695, Folder 5)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Nominating Committee (Box 695, Folder 6)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Printed Material (Box 696, Folder 1-2)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Rockefeller, Laurance S. (Box 697, Folder 1)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Rouse Study (Box 697, Folder 2)
    - Museums - South Street Seaport Museum - Working File (Leases) (Box 697, Folder 3)
    - Museums - Whitney Museum of Art (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Music - A-B (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Music - C-L (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
    - Music - M-Z (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
    - Music - Boston Symphony Orchestra, Inc. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Music - Carnegie Hall Society (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Music - The Cantata Singers, Inc. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Music - Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Music - Grand Teton Music Festival (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Music - Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Music - Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Paintings - A-Q (Box 36, Folder 2-4)
    - Paintings - R-Z (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Poetry (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Poetry - Academy of American Poets (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Publications - A (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Publications - B-G (Box 38, Folder 1-4)
    - Publications - H-M, P (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
    - Publications - N-O, Q-Z (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
    - Publications - Acknowledgement of Books - A-Z (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
    - Publications - American National Heritage Association (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Publications - Anchorage Daily News (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Publications - Andarade Victor (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Publications - Investigative Reports and Editors (IRE) (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Publications - Pacific News Service (Box 42, Folder 3-4)
    - Publications - Potomac Associates, Inc. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - A-Z (Box 43, Folder 2-3)
    - Publications - Readers Digest, 1972-1976 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - Board of Directors (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - Finances (Box 44, Folder 3-4)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - Finances - Audit and Investment Committees - Meetings-Minutes (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - Finances - International Operations (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - Board of Directors - Minutes-Meetings, 1976-1982 (Box 45, Folder 3, Box 46, Folder 1-3, Box 47, Folder 1-2)
    - Publications - Readers Digest - Printed Material (Box 47, Folder 3-4, Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Publications - "Seven Days" (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Restorations - A-M (Box 48, Folder 3-5)
    - Restorations - N-Z (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
    - Restorations - The Casements, Ormond Beach, FL (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Sculpture - A-Z (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
    - Theatre - A-C (Box 50, Folder 3-4)
    - Theatre - D-Z (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Aviation, 1977-1981; 3
    - Aviation - A-Z (Box 51, Folder 3-4)
    - Clippings (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Air Lines - A-M, 1977-1981 (Box 52, Folder 2-4)
    - Eastern Air Lines - N-Z, 1977-1981 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - Eastern Air Lines, 1972-1976 (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
    - Eastern Air Lines - A-Z, 1972-1976 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Board of Directors (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Board of Directors - Minutes-Meetings (Box 54, Folder 3-4, Box 55, Folder 1-2, Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Employees (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Executive Committee - Minutes-Meetings (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Miscellaneous Committees - Minutes-Meetings (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Finances - A-Z (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Finances (Box 57, Folder 1-3, Box 58, Box 59, Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Air Lines - National Airlines Merger (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Harper Woodward material (Box 60, Folder 3, Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Printed Matter (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Eastern Air Lines - Printed Material - Falcon (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - B-C, 1977-1981; 4
    - B - Miscellaneous (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
    - C - Miscellaneous (Box 62, Folder 3, Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Civic, 1977-1981; 5
    - Civic - A-C (Box 63, Folder 2-5)
    - Civic - D-Q (Box 64, Folder 1-5)
    - Civic - R-Z (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - American Civil Liberties Union Foundation (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - American Civil Liberties Union Foundation - Contributions (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - American Civil Liberties Union Foundation - Reports-Proposals (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Bill of Rights Foundation, Inc. (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Center for Constitutional Rights, Inc. (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Conference-Alternative State and Local Policies (Box 66, Folder 3, Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Council of Municipal Performance (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Hawaii Community Development Authority (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Inform, Inc. (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - League of Women Voters (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - League of Women Voters of the City of New York (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - New York Civil Liberties Union (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - OAHU Development Conference (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - OAHU Development Conference - Printed Matter (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - People for the American Way (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - New York City - A-E (Box 69, Folder 3-5)
    - New York City - F-Z (Box 70, Folder 1-2)
    - New York City - Bronx Frontier Development Corp. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - New York City - Citizens Committee for New York City (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - New York City - Citizens Budget Commission (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - New York City - Citizens Budget Commission - Printed Matter (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - New York City - Citizens Housing and Planning Council of NY, Inc. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - New York City - New York Board of Trade, Inc. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - New York City - Harlem Restoration Project, Inc. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - New York City - New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - New York City - New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry - Printed Matter (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - New York City - Regional Plan Association (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - New York City - Westway, 1977-1981 (Box 72, Folder 5, Box 73, Folder 1-2)
    - New York State - A-N (Box 73, Folder 3-4)
    - New York State - O-Z (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - New York State - State Insurance Fund (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - New York State - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller - Empire State Plaza (Box 74, Folder 3-4, Box 75, Folder 1)
    - New York State - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller - Empire State Plaza Council (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - New York State - Temporary State Commission on Restoration of the Capitol (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Government (Box 75, Folder 5-6)
    - U.S. Government - Bicentennial - A-Z (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
    - U.S. Government - National Commission on Water Quality (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Government - Printed Material (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Government - National Commission on Critical Choices for Americans (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Government - President's Commission on Executive Exchange (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Government - President's Commission on White House Fellowships (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Government - White House Preservation Fund (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Clubs, 1977-1981; 7
    - Clubs - A-C (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Clubs - C-M (Box 78, Folder 1-4)
    - Clubs - N-Z (Box 79, Folder 1-3)
    - Boone and Crockett Club (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Cosmos Club (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Cosmos Club - Printed Material (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Harbor Club (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Knickerbocker Club (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Knickerbocker Club - A-Z (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Knickerbocker Club - Finances (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Knickerbocker Club - Minutes-Meetings (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Links Golf Club (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Metropolitan Club of the City of Washington (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - The River Club (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Sleepy Hollow Country Club (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Tarrytown Boat Club (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - University Club (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Woodstock Golf and Tennis Club (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Woodstock Golf and Tennis Club - Finances, 1977-1981 (Box 82, Folder 3-4, Box 83, Folder 1-2)
  - Colonial Williamsburg, 1977-1981; 8
    - Colonial Williamsburg - A-L (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Colonial Williamsburg - M-Z (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Contributions (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Printed Matter (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Commercial Ventures, 1977-1981; 9
    - Commercial Ventures - A-C (Box 85, Folder 1-3)
    - Commercial Ventures - D-F (Box 86, Folder 1-4)
    - Commercial Ventures - F-I (Box 87, Folder 1-4)
    - Commercial Ventures - J-M (Box 88, Folder 1-3)
    - Commercial Ventures - N-R (Box 89, Folder 1-3)
    - Commercial Ventures - S-U (Box 90, Folder 1-3)
    - Commercial Ventures - V-Z (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Corporate Responsibility (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Clairfield Pallet, Inc. (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Dalli, Aloysius (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Fazenda Bodoquena, S.A. (Box 91, Folder 4-5)
    - Fazenda Bodoquena, S.A. - Finances (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Fazenda Bodoquena, S.A. - IRI Research Institute, Inc. (Box 92, Folder 2-3)
    - (George S.) Wills Associates (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Banking - A-Z (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - A-D (Box 93, Folder 3-4)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - E-R (Box 94, Folder 1-4)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - S-Z (Box 95, Folder 1-3)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - Annual Report (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - Board of Directors (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - International Advisory Committee (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - Center for Public Resources (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - Corporate Responsibility (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - Rockefeller, David - Retirement (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - Pahlavi, Mohammed Reza (Shah of Iran) - Clippings (Box 96, Folder 4, Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Insurance (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Conservation, 1977-1981; 10
    - Conservation - A-C (Box 97, Folder 3-5)
    - Conservation - D-L (Box 98, Folder 1-6)
    - Conservation - M-T (Box 99, Folder 1-5)
    - Conservation - U-Z (Box 100, Folder 1-2)
    - American Rivers Conservation Council (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Clippings (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Conservation Foundation (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Conservation Foundation - Contributions (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Conservation Foundation - Printed Material (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Conservation Law Fund of New England (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Council on Environmental Alternatives (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Environmental Action Foundation (Box 101, Folder 4-5)
    - Environmental Defense Fund (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Environmental Defense Fund - Contributions (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Environmental Policy Center (Box 102, Folder 3-4)
    - Environmental Policy Institute (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
    - Environmental Task Force (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Friends of the Earth Foundation (Box 103, Folder 4, Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Friends of the Earth Foundation - Printed Matter (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Island Resources Foundation (Box 104, Folder 3, Box 105, Folder 1)
    - National Audubon Society (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - National Audubon Society - Contributions (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - National Audubon Society - Printed Material (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - National Wildlife Federation (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. - A-T (Box 106, Folder 2-4)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. - U-Z (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. - Annual Reports (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. - Contributions (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. - Studies and Statements (Box 107, Folder 4, Box 108, Folder 1-2)
    - National Resources Defense Council, Inc. - Printed Material (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Natural Science for Youth Foundation (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Nature Conservancy Lower Hudson Chapter (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Nature Conservancy - Printed Material (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - New York Zoological Society (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - New York Zoological Society - A-E (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - New York Zoological Society - F-Z (Box 111, Folder 1-4)
    - New York Zoological Society - Animal Kingdom Fund (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - New York Zoological Society - Animal Research and Conservation Center (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - New York Zoological Society - Aquarium (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - New York Zoological Society - Board of Trustees (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - New York Zoological Society - Central Park Zoo (Prospect Park Zoo and Flushing Meadow Zoo) (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - New York Zoological Society - Conservation Committees (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - New York Zoological Society - Contributions (Box 112, Folder 5-6)
    - New York Zoological Society - Contributions - Animal Kingdom Fund (Box 112, Folder 7, Box 113, Folder 1)
    - New York Zoological Society - Contributions - Friends of Central Park Zoo (Box 113, Folder 2-3)
    - New York Zoological Society - Contributions - Miscellaneous - A-Z (Box 113, Folder 4-5)
    - New York Zoological Society - Finances (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - New York Zoological Society - Fund Raising (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - New York Zoological Society - Fund Raising - Animal Kingdom Fund (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - New York Zoological Society - Minutes-Meetings (Box 114, Folder 1-2)